<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-07-01T17:02:13-04:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><entry><title type="html">Apple’s 2020 WWDC</title><link href="/2020/06/23/Apple's-2020-WWDC.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Apple's 2020 WWDC" /><published>2020-06-23T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-06-23T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/2020/06/23/Apple's%202020%20WWDC</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2020/06/23/Apple's-2020-WWDC.html">&lt;p&gt;Every year Apple hosts their Worldwide Developer Conference (WWDC) and present their newest technology that they are developing or products that will be hitting the market in the fall. This year WWDC was no different. The 2 hour conference was divided up by products: iOS 14, watchOS, Home and macOS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;ios-14&quot;&gt;iOS 14&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/Apple 2020 WWDC/iOS 14.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;
This year Apple introduced many new features that took their user interface to look even better. Although most of the features like widgets, picture in picture has already been implemented on Android, Apple took it to the next step by making them more user friendly and gives user the ability to customize. Another key feature Apple has built into iOS 14 is giving users the ability to easily use their iPhone, this can be seen through making Siri not take up the entire screen when activated, app library that is categorized to easily be able to find the app that is being looked for. In my opinion there were two features that broke barriers&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1 .	The iPhone being able to act as a car key to BMW 2021 5-series with NFC and in the feature this could be applied to other wireless key cars using Apple’s U1 chip. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
2 .	The translate app that will be able to detect what language it picks up through the microphone and translate it to one of the eleven language. This will be able to be done when the iPhone is offline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;home&quot;&gt;Home&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/Apple 2020 WWDC/Home.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt; 
Apple Home is a newer product line relative to other product lines. Some of the new implementations that stood out in the conference was how tasks like locking doors, closing garage doors and turning off the lights could conveniently be hooked up and controlled from the iPhone. Another implementation that Apple presented was making the users TV able to access cameras around the house and use picture in picture just like iOS when someone enters the pre-set detection zone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;watchos&quot;&gt;watchOS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/Apple 2020 WWDC/WatchOS.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt; 
This year was no different than any other year’s conference Apple presented an update version of watchOS as it has in the past few years. Living in a time of a pandemic Apple has implemented a hand washing timer to make sure its user are washing their hand the right way. Along with hand washing timer Apple mainly focused on making the watchOS look more user friendly by letting users create their own watch home page and giving them the ability to share with their friend. When users discover an watch homepage by a third party they can easily apply it to their own watch and download the app needed to ensure they experience the greatest time with the new homepage they just downloaded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;macos&quot;&gt;macOS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/Apple 2020 WWDC/macOS.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt; 
This is a product line that many Apple enthusiasts looks forward to every year as the Mac was the product Apple started out with before developing all these different line that we know of today. This year Apple introduced a new macOS called the “Big Sur”. Apple’s goal with this version of the OS is to provide mac user with similar experience they get when using an iPhone by making the icons and logos highly identical and provide more privacy. 
Most importantly Apple confirmed a rumors that have been in the news.
Apple will now be making Macs with their own chips instead of Intel. This change will allow more cross platform app development to be done on all Apple device as they all run on the system now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;final-takeaways&quot;&gt;Final Takeaways&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 .	Apple continues to expand its ecosystem to trap more users into using their products and is attempting to use word of mouth by having user share with each other &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
2 . Apple may have just set the trend for the future with phones that can unlock cars. If this feature ends up being popular Apple has just taken a big lead in the market as car with wireless key are starting to become a norm &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
3 .	Apple creating its own chip instead of using Intel chip should reduce production cost and keep everything in house but at the same time R&amp;amp;D should also see an increase&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;full-wwdc&quot;&gt;Full WWDC&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;1000px&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/GEZhD3J89ZE&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><author><name>Beta X2 Investment Advisroy</name></author><category term="Apple" /><category term="Android" /><category term="AAPL" /><category term="NYSE" /><category term="NASDAQ" /><category term="INTC" /><category term="USA" /><summary type="html">Every year Apple hosts their Worldwide Developer Conference (WWDC) and present their newest technology that they are developing or products that will be hitting the market in the fall. This year WWDC was no different. The 2 hour conference was divided up by products: iOS 14, watchOS, Home and macOS. iOS 14 This year Apple introduced many new features that took their user interface to look even better. Although most of the features like widgets, picture in picture has already been implemented on Android, Apple took it to the next step by making them more user friendly and gives user the ability to customize. Another key feature Apple has built into iOS 14 is giving users the ability to easily use their iPhone, this can be seen through making Siri not take up the entire screen when activated, app library that is categorized to easily be able to find the app that is being looked for. In my opinion there were two features that broke barriers</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Alibaba’s future</title><link href="/2020/05/25/Alibaba-s-Future.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Alibaba’s future" /><published>2020-05-25T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-05-25T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/2020/05/25/Alibaba%E2%80%99s%20Future</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2020/05/25/Alibaba-s-Future.html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;description-of-business&quot;&gt;Description of Business&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alibaba started as a B2B marketplace in 1999. Jack Ma and his friends founded it in 1999 during the dot com rise in his apartment. Today it is the second-largest e-commerce platform lagging only Amazon and the most valuable company in Asia in 2019 by market cap. Besides e-commerce, the company also operate three different segments known as Cloud Computing, Digital Media and Entertainment and Innovation initiatives and others. Below is a revenue breakdown by segment and companies in each segment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/Alibaba's Future/Breakdown.png&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/Alibaba's Future/Alibaba-Segment-Companies.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alibaba has experienced success over the last two decades from having the highest IPO price for a technology stock ever at the time it public to where it is today. In the upcoming months there will be multiple key events happening. The events are analyzed below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;1-jack-mas-departure&quot;&gt;1. Jack Ma’s departure&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the last two decades when you talk about Alibaba the first name that comes to mind has been Jack Ma. Alibaba has been quietly changing that over the last few years with the last few step being taken on September 10th of 2018. On that day Jack Ma announced he will be stepping down from the position of Chairman at Alibaba in the coming year. Following that it has been reported that Jack Ma will be leaving the BOD after 2020 shareholders meeting which will be happening in June.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My thoughts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&quot; float:left; padding-right:20px;&quot; src=&quot;/images/Alibaba's Future/Daniel Zhang.jpg&quot; width=&quot;10%&quot; /&gt;
The price of Alibaba stock has priced in Jack Ma’s departure. He has spent the past few year slowly preparing Alibaba for this day. Starting from stepping down from CEO to stepping down from chairman to eventually leaving the BOD soon. 
Jack Ma’s successor, Daniel Zhang (seen on the left) should be able to take Alibaba greater heights although there will definitely be setback along the way as Alibaba’s main revenue segment, core commerce has reached maturity stage of the business growth cycle. Mr. Zhang would need to deploy a strategy that will continue to allow Alibaba’s revenue to grow at the rate it has in past years. Given Mr. Zhang track record of inventing Single’s Day that contributes to Alibaba recording breaking revenue every year, it is possible to believe he will come up with a strategy that will assist Alibaba to continue growing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;2-rising-us-and-china-tension&quot;&gt;2. Rising US and China Tension&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before COVID-19 hit US and China were under trade war that had investors predicting Alibaba would take a significant hit from as it would slow the growth of its expansion into the US and reduced consumer buying power in China due to tariffs applied on certain good. On January 15th 2020 the two country agreed on a phase 1 deal where both side agreed to rollback a portion of the tariffs, this led the market to believe that the tension between the two country was going back to normal. However it is possible that tension will come back as President Trump has been declaring for China to pay for the damage caused to other nation by COVID-19. At the same time China’s plan to take control of Hong Kong will not fair well between the two nations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My thoughts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alibaba has shown through the US and China trade war that it could continue to operate and grow as the trade war caused Chinese to buy more goods domestically and did not slow Alibaba’s earnings much. This could however lead revenue to take a hit as international commerce and retail made up 7% of total revenue and 8.5% of total commerce revenue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;3-senate-passing-hfcaa-on-us-regulated-listing&quot;&gt;3. Senate passing HFCAA on US regulated listing&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On May 20th the senates passed Holding Foreign Companies Accountable Act (HFCAA). The purpose of this act is to ensure companies that are listed on the US stock exchange are not owned or controlled by a foreign government. This act is viewed as targeted towards China, in the past Chinese companies have denied access to its audited work stating that it is against the Chinese laws for those documents to leave the country. The legislation still needs to be passed by the House of Representative before being passed onto President Trump.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My Thoughts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the legislation ends up getting pass the House of Representative and President Trump. It could lead to potential movement in the stock price as Alibaba is one of the 165 companies that was listed by SEC in 2019 to be affected by the legislation. If the worst case scenario of delisting occurs the stock will take a huge hit as investors will look to sell off before the stock becomes illiquid. This problem was also addressed on Q1 conference call as the projection of earnings growth was dropped to a lower amount due to multiple factors including this legislation.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Beta X2 Investment Advisroy</name></author><category term="Alibaba" /><category term="e-commerce" /><category term="BABA" /><category term="NYSE" /><category term="China" /><category term="USA" /><summary type="html">Description of Business Alibaba started as a B2B marketplace in 1999. Jack Ma and his friends founded it in 1999 during the dot com rise in his apartment. Today it is the second-largest e-commerce platform lagging only Amazon and the most valuable company in Asia in 2019 by market cap. Besides e-commerce, the company also operate three different segments known as Cloud Computing, Digital Media and Entertainment and Innovation initiatives and others. Below is a revenue breakdown by segment and companies in each segment.</summary></entry></feed>